<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chlöbo's Infosec Blog</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 01:44:56 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 01:44:56 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The obligatory '$WHOAMI?' and 'how did I end up in InfoSec?' post</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;The $WHOAMI bit...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m Chlöe - A enthusiastic Computer and Forensics Student at Leeds Beckett. At the time of writing this post, I am currently about to go on placement year as an interim Penetration Tester for Hedgehog Security. In my spare time I enjoy furthering my skills by undertaking projects, reading and attempting vulnerable machines with my friends. I also enjoy attending security conferences around the UK including BSides London, BSides Manchester and Securi-Tay! I am also a helper outer / organiser for BSides Leeds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/securitay.png&quot; alt=&quot;Securitay-Photo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The how I ended up here bit...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ok… so… like a lot of people my path into InfoSec is a bit is a bit unconventional…&lt;/em&gt; Despite always having a general interest in Computers, when I was younger I had a passion for film and tv editing and always believed I was going to follow a path into media and special effects. However, when I was 18 things changed. I got my first part time job and began hanging around with some somewhat questionable individuals. Sparing you the dark details the TL;DR was that I was very much made to believe that studying at sixth form was a poor choice and instead after 2 years of study, I was influenced to drop out and continue my further education studying on a City and Guilds IT qualification at a local college. Unfortunately for me, the course really didn’t suit me and despite enjoying the course content I ended up exiting the course and taking up full time employment at a bar in my local town. With only 1 A-Level and 3 AS Levels I found myself very stuck and very unhappy. &lt;em&gt;Where things changed…&lt;/em&gt; Luckily, my circumstances changed and I was lucky enough to find myself around some amazing people who gave me the confidence and the help to turn things around. I applied to study on a few foundation degree courses and shortly after I was enrolled on an ‘Applied Computing’ foundation Degree. After a long year of hard work I then applied for a full degree course at Leeds Beckett and successfully got a place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/bsides.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bsides-Photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The happily ever after bit...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward, I have now recently finished the second year of my course and I am incredibly happy. I have had a number of amazing opportunities including being the secretary for the Leeds Hacking Society (17/18) and being able to help organise BSides Leeds this year.
The InfoSec community is genuinely one of the most accepting and lovely communities going and I am incredibly thankful for all the support I have received since being a part of it. I think the moral of the story here is that no matter your background there is always a way in so don’t give up!
A honourable mention to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LargeCardinal&quot;&gt;@LargeCardinal&lt;/a&gt; for always telling me to #tryharder and for teaching me some really cool shiz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So whats the point of this blog..?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to start this blog to document all the things I am doing and to hopefully give the perspective of learning security from the perspective of someone who is learning the skills of industry from the very beginning. I will add a disclaimer here that my posts might be a little rambley - I want to document things that haven’t worked for me as well as things that have - that way others might be able to learn from my mistakes and I will have resources to refer back to!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/05/01/whoami/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/05/01/whoami/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
